Register of the National Republic records, 1918-1960
Hoover Institution Archives
- Communist Party Pamphlet File, 1920-1956 (Boxes 407-415)
  - Aluf, A. "The Development of Socialist Methods and Forms of Labor,", 1932
  - American Association for International Conciliation. "Some Bolshevist Portraits,", 1920
  - Amter, Israel
    - "Industrial Slavery - Roosevelt's 'New Deal,'", 1933
    - "The March Against Hunger,", 1933
    - "May Day 1939,"
    - "Social Security in a Soviet America,", 1935
    - "The Truth about the Communists,", undated
    - "The Truth about Finland,", undated
    - "Why the Workers' Unemployment Insurance Bill?,", 1934
    - "Working Class Unity or Fascism?,", 1935
  - Andrews, Lillian. "Youth of the Happy Land,", undated
  - Anstrom, George. "The Government Takes a Hand...In the Cotton Patch,", 1933
  - Aptheker, Herbert. "The Labor Movement in the South during Slavery,", 1955
  - Ault, Leslie. "Challenge to Fear,", 1938
  - Avdeyeva, K. "The Trade Unions and Socialist Construction in the U.S.S.R.,", 1929
  - Baarslag, Karl. "Communist Trade Union Trickery Exposed,", 1949
  - Ballam, John. "70,000 Silk Workers Strike for Bread and Unity,", 1934
  - Barnett, John
    - "Farm-Dollar Blight: The 'New Deal' in Agriculture,", 1933
    - "The Farmers' Way Out: Life under a Workers' and Farmers' Government,", 1935
    - "Speeding Up the Workers,", 1930
  - Berger, Mrs. Victor. "I Saw Russia: Socialism in the Making,", undated
  - Bittelman, Alex
    - "The Advance of the United Front,", 1934
    - "Break the Economic and Political Sabotage of the Monopolists,", undated
    - "The Communist Party in Action,", 1934
    - "Fifteen Years of the Communist Party,", 1934
    - "From Left-Socialism to Communism,", 1933
    - "Going Left: The Left Wing Formulates a 'Draft for a Program for the Socialist Party of the United States,'", 1936
    - "How Can we Share the Wealth? The Communist Way versus Huey Long,", 1935
    - "Jewish Unity for Victory,", 1943
    - "Milestones in the History of the Communist Party,", 1937
    - "Problems of Party Building,", 1937
    - "Revolutionary Struggle Against War vs. Pacifism,", undated
  - Blagoyeva, Stella D. "Dimitroff: Aus dem Leben eines Revolutionaers,", 1934
  - Blake, Ben, ed. "12 Plays for Boys and Girls,", undated
  - Briggs, H. E. "New Deal for the Vets,", 1933
  - Browder, Earl
    - "America's Decisive Battle,", 1945
    - "China and the U.S.A.,", 1937
    - "Civil War in Nationalist China,", 1927
    - "The Communist Party of the U.S.A.,", 1941
    - "The Communist Position in 1936,"
    - "Communists and National Unity,", 1944
    - "The Communists in the People's Front,", 1937
    - "Concerted Action or Isolation: Which is the Road to Peace?,", 1938
    - "The Constitution of the United States,", 1942
    - "The Democratic Front,", 1938
    - "Economic Problems of the War and Peace,", 1944
    - "The Economics of Communism: The Soviet Economy in Its World Relation,", 1939
    - "Eyes on Washington! A Program for People's Legislation: What Labor and the People Can Do to Influence Congress in 1956,", 1955
    - "Fighting for Peace,", 1939
    - "The Future of the Anglo-Soviet-American Coalition,", 1943
    - "George Dimitroff,", undated
    - "Hearst's 'Secret' Documents in Full,", 1936
    - "How Do We Raise the Question of a Labor Party?,", 1935
    - "Internationalism. Results of the 1940 Election,"
    - "Is Communism a Menace?,", 1943
    - "Keynes, Foster and Marx, Part II: Progress and Socialism,", 1950
    - "Lincoln and the Communists,", 1936
    - "The Meaning of the Elections,", 1944
    - "The Meaning of Social-Fascism: Its Historical and Theoretical Background,", 1933
    - "A Message to Catholics,", 1938
    - "New Steps in the United Front,", 1935
    - "Next Steps to Win the War in Spain,", 1938
    - "The 1940 Elections: How the People can Win,", 1939
    - "North America and the Soviet Union,", 1937
    - "One Year since Pearl Harbor,", 1942
    - "Out of a Job,", undated
    - "The Path of Browder and Foster,", 1941 (Box 408)
    - "The People Against the War-Makers,", 1940
    - "The People's Road to Peace,", 1940
    - "Policy for Victory,", 1942
    - "Religion and Communism,", 1935
    - "Report to the 8th Convention, Communist Party,", 1934
    - "Reports to the 9th Convention of the Communist Party,", 1936
    - "The Results of the Elections and the People's Front,", 1936
    - "The Road Ahead to Victory and Lasting Peace,", 1944
    - "The Second Imperialist War,", 1940
    - "Secret Hoover-Laval War Pacts,", 1931
    - "Social and National Security,", 1938
    - "Stop the War,", 1939
    - "Study Guide and Outline for The People's Front,", undated
    - "Talks to America,", 1937
    - "Teheran and America,", 1944
    - "Traitors in American History: Lessons of the Moscow Trials,", 1938
    - "Victory - and After,", 1942
    - "Victory Must be Won,", 1942
    - "Wage Policy in War Production,", 1943
    - "What Every Worker Should Know about NRA,", 1933
    - "What Is Communism?,", 1936
    - "What Is the New Deal?,", 1933
    - "Who Are the Americans?,", 1936
    - "World Communism and U.S. Foreign Policy,", 1948
  - Brown, F. "Who are the Communists and What Do They Stand For?,", 1936
  - Bubnov, A. "Leninism,", 1934
  - Budenz, Louis F.
    - "May Day 1937: What It Means to You,"
    - "May Day 1940: What It Means to You,"
    - "Red Baiting: Enemy of Labor,", 1937
  - Bulazel, C. "Stop Munitions,", undated
  - Bulganin, Nikolai A. "Report on Directives of the 20th Congress of the C.P.S.U. for the Sixth Five-Year Plan for the Development of the U.S.S.R., 1956-1960,"
  - Butenko, Th. "Enthullunger ueber Moskau,", 1938
  - Cable, George W. "A Southerner Looks at Racial Discrimination,", 1946
  - Cacchione, Peter V. "Public Speaking: A Speaker's Guide Book,", 1942
  - Cameron, Donald A. "Chemical Warfare,", 1930
  - Campion, Martha. "New Pioneer Story Book,", 1935 (Box 409)
  - Casey, James. "Hearst: Labor's Enemy No. 1,", 1935
  - Claessens, August. "The Trinity of Plunder,", 1922
  - Clark, Joseph
    - "Men of Liberty,", 1942
    - "We the People,", 1937
  - Communist League of America. "War and the 4th International,", 1934
  - Communist Party of Germany
    - "Der Ausweg aus der Bauernnot: Sowjetmacht besiegt Bauernnot,", undated
    - "Deutsche Arbeiter, faengt an!,", 1934
    - "Deutsche Zentral - Zeitung,", undated
    - "Duetschland - Information des Zentrallkomitees der K.P.D.,", 1938
    - "Hundert Tage illegaler Kampf,", 1933
    - "Internationale Literatur,", 1933
    - "Die Kommunistische Internationale,", 1935
    - "Die Neue Weltbuehne,", 1938
    - "Nieder mit dem Krieg,", undated
    - "Programm der Kommunistischen Internationale,", 1928
    - "Redes des Fuehrers und Reichkanzlers Adolf Hitler vor dem Reichstag am 21. Mai 1935,", undated
    - "Rundschau ueber Politik, Wirtschaft und Arbeiter-bewegung,", 1938
    - "Der Spruch von London,", undated
    - "Unsere Zeit,", 1934
  - Communist Party of the Soviet Union
    - "Constitution (Fundamental Law) of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics,", 1936
    - "The National Economic Plan of the U.S.S.R. for 1937,"
    - "On the Organization of Party Propaganda in Connection with the Publication of the History of the C.P.S.U. (B.) Short Course,", 1939
    - "Resolutions of the 20th Congress of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union,", 1956
    - "The Soviet Law on Marriage,", 1933
  - Communist Party of the United States of America
    - "Acceptance Speeches: Communist Candidates in the Presidential Elections,", 1936
    - "The American Legion and the Communists Discuss Democracy,", 1938
    - "Another War Coming!,", undated
    - "Capitalist Stabilization has Ended,", 1932
    - "Catholics and the Civil War in Spain,", 1936
    - "Communist Election Platform: Against Imperialist War For Jobs and Bread,", 1932
    - " The Communist Manifesto in Pictures,", 1948
    - "The Communist Position on the Farmers' Movement,", 1933
    - "Communists in the Struggle for Negro Rights,", 1945
    - "A Confession of Faith: We State Our Case to the Legislative Committee,", undated
    - "The Constitution and By-Laws of the Communist Party of the United States of America,", 1938
    - "Declaration and Principles and Constitution of the Workers Party of the U.S.,", undated
    - "Discussion Bulletin,", 1956
    - "Draft Resolution of the 16th National Convention of the Communist Party, U.S.A.,", 1956
    - "Every Worker Should Join the Communist Party,", undated
    - "Fascist War on Women,", undated
    - "For United Action Against Fascism,", 1933 (Box 410)
    - "Fundamentals of Communism,", undated
    - "Hitler Against the World; The World Against Hitler,", 1935
    - "How to Organize Mass Meetings,", 1939
    - "International Review,", 1941
    - "Manual for Community Club Leaders,", 1944
    - "On the Road to Bolshevization,", 1929
    - "An Open Letter to All Members of the Communist Party,", 1933
    - "The Paris Commune (March 28 to May 28, 1871),", 1926
    - "Party Building: A Handbook for Branch Officers,", undated
    - "Party Building and Political Leadership,", 1937
    - "The Path to Peace, Progress and Prosperity: Proceedings of the Constitutional Convention of the Communist Political Association,", 1944
    - "A People's Constitution for New York,", undated
    - "Platform of Struggle for Urgent Needs of Toilers: Election Platform of the Communist Party, New York State, 1934,"
    - "Political Education: The Communist Party,", 1935
    - "Political Education: The Ultimate Aim,", undated
    - "Preparing for October: The Historic Sixth Congress of the Boshevik Party,", undated
    - "Program of the Communist International,", undated
    - "Race Hatred on Trial,", 1931
    - "The Red Army,", 1934
    - "Resolutions of the Ninth Convention of the Communist Party,", 1936
    - "Resolutions of the 10th Convention of the Communist Party U.S.A,", 1938
    - "Shall the Communist Party Change Its Name?,", 1944
    - "Shop Paper Manual,", 1931
    - "The Struggle Against Imperialist War and the Tasks of the Communists,", 1934
    - "Struggles Ahead: Thesis on the Economic and Political Situation and the Tasks of the Communist Party,", 1930
    - "Twentieth Century Americanism: What Does Every American Family Want?,", undated
    - "Unity Will Conquer,", 1936
    - "We Gather Strength,", 1933
    - "What Is the Five Year Plan?,", undated
    - "What You Should Know about the Communists,", 1947
    - "The White Terrorists Ask for Mercy: A Comparison of the Persecution of Revolutionists by the White Terror and the Treatment of Counter-Revolutionists in Soviet Russia,", 1925
  - Cooper, Leo. "Program for Peace or Weapon for War?,", 1948
  - Cowl, Margaret. "The Soviet Union: Your Questions Answered,", 1934
  - Cruden, Robert L. "The End of the Ford Myth,", 1932
  - Darcy, Samuel Adams. "The Battle for Production,", 1942
  - David, Rex, "Schools and the Crisis,", 1934
  - Dennis, Eugene (Box 411)
    - "America at the Crossroads: Postwar Problems and Communist Policy,", 1945
    - "The Elections and the Outlook for National Unity,", 1944
    - "I Challenge the Un-Americans,", 1947
    - "Is Communism Un-American?,", 1947
    - "Peace or War: The People Against the Warmakers,", 1946
    - "The People Against the Trusts,", 1946
    - "The Red-Baiters Menace in America,", 1946
    - "What America Faces: The New War Danger and the Struggle for Peace, Democracy and Economic Security,", 1946
  - Dietrich, P. R. "Towards the World October,", undated
  - Dimitrov, Georgi
    - "Brief an die Osterreichischen Arbeiter,", 1934
    - "Resolutions: Seventh Congress of the Communist International,", 1935
    - "The Soviet Union and the Working Class of the Capitalist Countries,", 1937
    - "Spain and the People's Front,", 1937
    - "The United Front Against Fascism and War,", 1935
    - "The War and the Working Class,", 1939
    - "Wie kann Ernst Thaelmann gerettet werden?,", 1934
    - "The Working Class Against Fascism: Dimitrov's Speech to the Seventh Congress of the Communist International,", 1935
    - "Working Class Unity - Bulwark Against Fascism,", 1935
  - Duclos, Jacques. "Communism, Science and Culture,", 1939
  - Dunn, Robert W.
    - "The Bill of Rights in Danger,", 1940
    - "Company Unions Today,", 1935
    - "Spying on Workers,", 1933
    - "What War Means to the Workers,", 1933
  - Dunne, William F.
    - "The Great San Francisco General Strike,", 1934
    - "Permanent Counter-Revolution,", 1934
    - "The Supreme Court's Challenge to Labor,", 1935
    - "Why Hearst Lies about Communism,", 1935
  - Dutt, R. Palme and Ivor Montagu. "Ruby Star,", undated
  - Eisman, Harry. "An American Boy in the Soviet Union,", 1934
  - Epstein, M. "May Day 1934,", undated
  - Ercoli, M. "The Fight for Peace,", 1935
  - Fischer, Ernst
    - "Murder at the Kemerovo Mines: Trotskyite Plotters at Work,", 1937
    - "What is Socialism?,", 1940
  - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley
    - "Meet the Communists,", 1946
    - "Women Have a Date with Destiny,", 1944
  - Ford, James W. and Harry Gannes. "War in Africa: Italian Fascism Prepares to Enslave Ethiopia,", 1935
  - Foster, William Z.
    - "Communism versus Fascism,", 1941
    - "Fight Against Hunger,", 1930
    - "Industrial Unionism,", 1936
    - "The Menace of American Imperialism,", 1945
    - "The Menace of a New World War,", 1946
    - "Organized Labor Faces the New World,", 1945
    - "Organizing Methods in the Steel Industry,", 1936
    - "Our Country Needs a Strong Communist Party,", 1946
    - "The People and the Congress,", 1943
    - "Problems of Organized Labor Today,", 1946
    - "Questions and Answers on the Piatakov-Radek Trial,", 1937
    - "The Rankin Witch Hunt,", 1945
    - "Reaction Beats Its War Drums,", 1946
    - "The Soviet Trade Unions and Allied Labor Unity,", 1943
    - "The Strike Situation and Organized Labor's Wage and Job Strategy,", 1945
    - "Unionizing Steel,", 1936
    - "The United States and the Soviet Union,", 1940
    - "What Means a Strike in Steel?,", 1937
    - "Workers, Defend Your Unions!,", 1947
    - "Your Questions Answered,", 1939
  - Fraternal Orders Conference. "Fraternal Orders Speak for Unionization of the Steel Industry,", 1936
  - Gannes, Harry. "Spain Defends Democracy,", 1936
  - Gannett, Betty, "The Communist Party and You,", 1947
  - Garlin, Sender. "Is Dewey the Man?,", 1944
  - George, Harrison
    - "A Noon-Hour Talk on the Communist Party,", undated
    - "This 4th of July,", 1937
  - Gomez, Manuel, ed. "Poems for Workers: An Anthology,", undated
  - Gordon, Eugene and Cyril Briggs. "The Position of Negro Women,", 1935
  - Gordon, F. "First Grade Reader,", 1935
  - Gorky, Maxim
    - "To American Intellectuals,", 1932
    - "To Foreign Workers,", 1931
  - Green, Gil
    - "The Truth about Soviet Russia,", 1938
    - "United We Stand - For Peace and Socialism,", 1935
    - "Young Communists and Unity of the Youth,", 1935
    - "Youth Confronts the Blue Eagle,", 1933
  - Groetz, R. "Ernst Thaelmann: The Leader of the German Workers,", 1934
  - Hallgren. Mauritz A. "Why I Resigned from the Trotsky Defense Committee,", 1937
  - Harris, Lem. "Meat: A National Scandal,", 1946
  - Hart, Harold. "The Cry for Peace,", 1936
  - Hathaway, C. A.
    - "Collective Security: The Road to Peace,", 1938
    - "Communists in the Textile Strike: An Answer to Gorman, Green & Co.,", 1934
    - "The People vs. the Supreme Court,", 1937
    - "Why a Workers' Daily Press?,", undated
  - Haywood, H. and M. Howard. "Lynching,", 1932
  - Heller, Arthur A.
    - "Laughter in Hell,", undated
    - "1/6 of the World,", undated
  - Herndon, Angelo, "The Scottsboro Boys,", 1937
  - Honig, Nathaniel. "The Trade Unions since the NRA,", 1934
  - Howard, Milton. "This 4th of July,", 1938
  - Hudson, Roy
    - "Communists and the Trade Unions,", 1943
    - "Post-War Jobs for Veterans, Negroes, Women,", 1944
    - "Trends in the Labor Movement,", 1941
    - "Who Are the Reds?,", 1937
  - Hutchins, Grace (Box 412)
    - "The Truth about the Liberty League,", 1936
    - "What Every Working Woman Wants,", 1935
    - "Women who Work" [2 different pamphlets], 1952
    - "Youth in Industry,", 1932
  - Hyman, Nancy and Leonard Sparks. "Public Enemy No. 1: William Randolph Hearst,", 1935
  - International Labor Defense
    - "The International Labor Defense: Its Constitution and Organization Resolution,", 1929
    - "Under Arrest: Workers' Self-Defense in the Courts,", undated
  - International Trade Union Committee of Negro Workers. "The Negro Worker,", 1936
  - International Workers Order
    - "A New Workers' Stronghold,", 1930
    - "Why Every Worker Should Join the International Workers Order,", 1932
  - International Workers Order, Junior Section and National Pioneer Council
    - "Games for Workers' Children,", undated
    - "Poems and Recitations,", undated
  - Jarrboe, George. "The Unknown Soldier Speaks,", 1932
  - Jenks, M. "The Communist Nucleus--What It Is--How It Works,", 1928
  - Jerome, V. J. "Intellectuals and the War,", 1940
  - Jones, Claudia. "Lift Every Voice for Victory,", 1942
  - Jones, Hays. "Seamen and Longshoremen under the Red Flag,", 1935
  - Jorge. "Red Sparks,", 1931
  - Kameneff, L. "The Dictatorship of the Proletariat,", 1920
  - Katz, M. "The Assassination of Kirov: Proletarian Justice vs. White-Guard Terror,", 1935
  - Kay, Helen
    - "Battle in the Barnyard: Stories and Pictures for Workers' Children,", 1932
    - "We Demand a Story of Any Boy and Any Girl,", undated
  - King, Emerson, Renaud, and McRyn. "We Accuse (From the Record),", undated
  - Knorin, V. "Fascism, Social Democracy and the Communists,", 1934
  - Kollontai, Alexandra. "Communism and the Family,", undated
  - Komor, I. "Ten Years of the Communist International,", 1929
  - Kozlov, V. "Bourgeois Nations and Socialist Nations,", 1954
  - Kravif, Hy. "Tel and Tel: The Telephone and Telegraph Workers,", 1935
  - Krumbein, Charless and Israel Amter. "Dollars for Democracy,", undated
  - Kun, Bela. "Unity of Action,", 1934
  - Kurella, Alfred. "The Five-Year Plan and the Cultural Revolution,", undated
  - Kuusinen, O.
    - "Die Front der Jungen Generation,", 1935
    - "Prepare for Power: The International Situation and the Tasks of the Sections of the Comintern,", undated
    - "Youth and Fascism,", 1935
  - Labor Research Department. "The Two Classes,", 1935
  - Lang, P. "Peace vs. War: The Communist Position,", 1936
  - Lapin, Adam
    - "The Un-American Dies Committee,", 1939
    - "Your Stake in the Elections,", 1944
  - Lasswell, James. "Shovels and Guns: The CCC in Action,", 1935
  - Lawson, Elizabeth
    - "Lincoln's Third Party,", 1948
    - "The Spy at Your Counter,", undated
    - "Thaddeus Stevens: Militant Democrat and Fighter for Negro Rights,", 1942
  - Lenin, Vladimir I.
    - "Capitalism and Agriculture in the United States,", 1934
    - "The Foundation of the Communist International,", 1934
    - "Imperialism: The Highest Stage of Capitalism,", 1933
    - "Left Communism: An Infantile Disorder,", undated
    - "Lenin on the Jewish Question,", 1934
    - "Lenin Speaks to the Youth,", 1936
    - "A Letter to American Workers,", 1934
    - "On the Eve of October,", 1932
    - "The Paris Commune,", 1934
    - "The Soviets at Work,", undated
    - "State and Revolution,", 1932
    - "The Tasks of the Proletariat in Our Revolution,", 1932
    - "The Tasks of the Youth Leagues,", 1953
  - Levi, Maxine. "The Communists and the Liberation of Europe,", 1945 (Box 413)
  - Lewis, H. H. "Thinking of Russia,", 1932
  - Liberov, Alexei B. "I Was...a Communist!,", 1936
  - Lovestone, Jay
    - "Blood and Steel: An Exposure of the 12-Hour Day in the Steel Industry,", undated
    - "The Coolidge Program: Capitalist Democracy and Prosperity Exposed,", 1927
    - "Pages from Party History,", undated
  - Lumer, Hyman. "The Professional Informer,", 1955
  - Luxemburg, Rosa. "The Mass Strike: The Political Party and the Trade Union,", undated
  - Magil, A. B.
    - "America Needs Earl Browder,", 1941
    - "The People's Message to Congress,", 1938
    - "Socialism: What's In It for You?,", 1946
  - Magnus, Edward. "Professionals in a Soviet America,", 1935
  - Manevich, E. D. "Second Grade Reader,", 1935
  - Manuilsky, D. Z.
    - "Engels in the Struggle for Revolutionary Marxism,", 1936
    - "The Revolutionary Crisis is Maturing,", 1934
    - "Revolutionary Crisis, Fascism and War,", 1934
  - Marion, George. "The 'Free Press' Portrait of a Monopoly,", 1946
  - Marx, Karl and Friedrich Engels, "The Communist Manifesto,", 1935
  - Marx, Karl. "Wage Labor and Capital,", 1933
  - Max, Alan. "May Day 1938: For Democracy, Jobs, Security, Peace,"
  - Michal, Wolf. "Youth Marches toward Socialism,", 1936
  - Miller, Moses. "Crisis in Palestine,", 1946
  - Mindel, J.
    - "The Economic System, Political Structure and Foreign Policy of the Soviet Union, and American-Soviet Collaboration,", undated
    - "The Nature of the War and Problems of the War Economy,", 1944
  - Minor, Robert
    - "The Heritage of the Communist Political Association,", undated
    - "How Ben Davis Was Elected,", 1946
    - "Invitation to Join the Communist Party,", 1943
    - "Lynching and Frame-Up in Tennessee,", 1946
  - Mitchell, Louise
    - "America's Housing Crisis,", 1946
    - "Food Prices and Rationing,", 1943
    - "Hold that Rent Ceiling,", 1947
  - Molotov, V. M.
    - "The International Situation and the Soviet Union,", 1935
    - "The Meaning of the Soviet-German Non-Aggression Pact,", 1939
    - "Molotov on the New Soviet Constitution,", 1937
    - "The New Phase in the Soviet Union,", 1930
    - "Die Politik des Aufbaus und des Friedens,", 1936
  - Morris, George
    - "The Black Legion Rides,", 1936
    - "How Wall Street Picks Your Pocket,", 1946
    - "Labor Unity: What AFL-CIO Merger Means for Workers,", 1955
    - "Reconversion: 60,000,000 Jobs or 15,000,000 Jobless,", 1945
    - "The Red-Baiting Racket,", 1947
    - "The Smith...McCarran...Taft Hartley Conspiracy to Strangle Labor,", 1951
    - "The Trotskyite 5th Column in the Labor Movement,", 1945
  - Motleva, V. "Youth in the World War,", undated
  - Muehlen, Herminia zur. "Fairy Tales for Workers Children,", 1925
  - Murray, Sean
    - "Ireland's Fight for Freedom and the Irish in the U.S.A.,", 1934
    - "Ireland's Path to Freedom: Manifesto of the Communist Party of Ireland,", 1934
    - "The Irish Case for Communism,", 1934
    - "The Irish Revolt - 1916 and After,", undated
  - National Republic Magazine. "Leninism--Lewisism,", undated
  - Neumann, Heinz. "Marx and Engels on Revolution in America,", undated
  - Neumann, Franz. "European Trade Unionism and Politics,", 1936
  - Nikolsky, N. M. "History: A Textbook for Middle Schools,", 1935
  - North, Joseph. "Washington and Lincoln: The American Tradition,", 1942
  - Olgin, M. J. "Why Communism? Plain Talks on Vital Problems,", 1934
  - Page, Myra. "Southern Cotton Mills and Labor,", 1934
  - Pen and Hammer. "Don't Take it Lying Down,", 1933
  - Pendrell, Nan and Ernest. "How the Rich Live, and Whom to Tax,", 1939
  - Peters, J. "The Communist Party: A Manual on Organization,", 1935
  - Piatnitsky, O. (Box 414)
    - "The Bolshevization of the Communist Parties,", undated
    - "The Immediate Tasks of the International Trade-Union Movement,", undated
    - "Problems der internationalen Gewerkschafts- Bewegung,", 1934
    - "The Work of the Communist Parties of France and Germany and the Tasks of the Communists in the Trade Union Movement,", undated
    - "World Communists in Action,", undated
  - Pieck, Wilhelm
    - "Aufgaben und Zielsetzung der Einheitsfront,", 1935
    - "Freedom, Peace and Bread!,", 1935
  - Pritt, D. N. "At the Moscow Trial,", 1937
  - Quin, Mike. "The Enemy Within,", 1941
  - Radek, Karl. "The Architect of Socialist Society,", 1935